Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
- I. Papers
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1942-1951; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (6 pages); Rosenfeld, L., (Leon), 1904-1974 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 11)
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letters to Fritz London, 3 letters, 1933.
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1935-1937; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (3 pages); Rosenthal, J. E. (Reel 54, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 26 February 1920 - 1 July 1921; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (17 pages); Rosseland, Svein, 1894-1985 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Dirk Coster, 11 April 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Rosseland, Svein, 1894-1985 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to James Franck, 9 March 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Rosseland, Svein, 1894-1985 (Reel BSC 2, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 18 March 1925 - 7 April 1950; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Rosseland, Svein, 1894-1985 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 9, Reel 13, Reel-frame 11)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 34 letters, 1924-1959.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letter to C. W. Oseen, 1934.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1952; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (11 pages); Royal Society of Edinburgh. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946-1952; 8.0 Item(s) 8 letters (17 pages); Rozental, S., (Stefan) (Reel 13, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 15 May 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Rozhdestvenskii, D. S., (Dmitrii Sergeevich), 1876-1940 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 5 February 1935 - 27 September 1935; 9.0 Item(s) 9 letters (13 pages); Ruark, Arthur Edward, 1899-1979 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 16 July 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Ruark, Arthur Edward, 1899-1979 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 19)
  - Letters to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 2 July 1928 - 5 July 1928; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Ruark, Arthur Edward, 1899-1979; Urey, Harold Clayton, 1893-1981 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 9 August 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Ruark, Arthur Edward, 1899-1979 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to J. H. Van Vleck, 22 March 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Ruark, Arthur Edward, 1899-1979 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 13)
  - Critical remarks on an early draft of Van Vleck's National Research Council Bulletin, Quantum Principles and Line Spectra, March 1924; 33.0 p.; Ruark, Arthur Edward, 1899-1979 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 10 May 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Rubens, Heinrich, 1865-1922 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, November 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Rubens, Heinrich, 1865-1922 (Reel 43, Reel-frame 4)
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. Letters to Ludwig Darmstaedter, 1909; to Flügge, 1917; to Hans Geitel, 1907; to Max Iklé, 1908; to Karl Scheel, 1914; to von Waldeyer-Hartz, 1916; to Eilhard Wiedemann, 1916; 3 letters to unknown recipient, 1903. 2 letters to Lebenslaufe, 1890-1892, for the Kultusministerium, Berlin. 2 announcements of his lectures. (Darmstaedter Collection, Flc 1897). 3 letters to Luschan, 1917-1919. (Nachlass Luschan).
    Universitätsbibliothek, Erlangen, Germany. Rubens' response to an invitation of the Societas Physicomedica in Erlangen to their centennial celebration, 1908. (Ms 2565/6).
    Deutsches Museum, Munich, Germany. Letter to Wilhelm Feddersen, 1908; letter to Leo Graetz, 1904; 4 letters to Heinrich Hertz, 1890; letter to Carl Runge, 1904.
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1915; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (7 pages); Rubin, Edgar, 1886-1951 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 7 October 1919 - 16 November 1922; 22.0 Item(s) 22 letters (50 pages); Rubinowicz, Adalbert, (Wojciech), 1889-1974 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 9 July 1922 - 1949; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (10 pages); Rubinowicz, Adalbert, (Wojciech), 1889-1974 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 11, Reel 10, Reel-frame 10, Reel 8, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936-1949; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (9 pages); Rubinowicz, Adalbert, (Wojciech), 1889-1974 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 6)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 2 letters, 1962.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letter to C. W. Oseen, 1914.
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1913; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Rudorf, George, b. 1881 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 8 October 1923; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Runge, Carl, 1856-1927 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 2 September 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Runge, Carl, 1856-1927 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 19)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1923.
    Westdeuschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. Some material [amount unspecified]. (Darmstaedter Collection, H 1885 11).
    Bayerische Staatsbibliothek, Munich, Germany. Minute on Runge's admission to the Gesellschaft d. Wiss., Göttingen 1922. (Amiraiana VIII, 11).
    Deutsches Museum, Munich, Germany. 2 letters to Heinrich Hertz, 1893; letter to Walter Kaufmann, 1903; 2 letters to Woldemar Voigt, 1901-1904.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to Hermann Weyl, 1925.
  - Selected Letters, 1.0 Reel(s); Runge, Carl, 1856-1927 (Reel 87)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1950-1952; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (4 pages); Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 19 June 1939; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Russell, Henry Norris, 1877-1957 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 6)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 2 letters, 1923-1924.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. Letters to Heinrich Kayser, 2 letters, 1913. (Darmstaedter Collection, Flc 1913).
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 2 letters, 1936-1937.
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1927-1930; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (8 pages); Rutgers, A. J., (Arend Joan) (Reel 61, Reel-frame 5, Reel 64, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1946; 21.0 Item(s) 21 letters (57 pages); Rutgers, A. J., (Arend Joan) (Reel 13, Reel-frame 13, Reel 10, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1951; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (6 pages); Rutgers, A. J., (Arend Joan) (Reel 37, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1950; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Rutgers, Gerrit Arnoldus Wijnand (Reel 12, Reel-frame 16)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 27 January 1912 - 25 November 1922; 45.0 Item(s) 45 letters (107 pages); Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 20 September 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Reel 61, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Werner Heisenberg, 26 March 1934; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Reel 45, Reel-frame 2)
  - Correspondence, 6.0 Reel(s); Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Reel AHQP/RTD 1-6)
    Cambridge University Library, Cambridge, England.
    Described in: Rutherford Correspondence Catalog, compiled by Lawrence Badash. New York: American Institute of Physics, 1974.
  - Lecture on nuclear physics, Göttingen, 1932; 7.0 p.; Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Reel 78, Reel-frame 1)
    Incomplete.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to P. M. S. Blackett, 1937; to Neils Bohr, 1935-1937; to Bertram Borden Boltwood, 1904-1924; to Max Born, 1936; 3 letters to R. W. Boyle, 1916-1936; to William Henry Bragg, 1911-1916; to P. W. Burbidge, 1936; to Sir James Chadwick, 1925-1936; to William Crookes, 1902; to Madame P. Curie, 1910; to George Gamow, 1937; to Hans Geiger, 1912-1937; to 0tto Hahn, 1906-1937; to V. F. Hess, 1936; to Georg von Hevesy, 1912-1937; to Frederic Joliot-Curie, 1936; to Irene Joliot-Curie, 1935; to Petr Kapitsa, 1925, other letters uncatalogued; to Irving Langmuir, 1937; to E. O. Lawrence, 1935-1937; to Lord Linlithgow, 1936; to Stefan Meyer, 1910-1937; correspondence about printing of Moseley photograph for distribution, 1925; to Hans Petterson, 1925; 2 letters to W. Ramsay, 1907; to Baron Rayleigh, 1907; to Johannes Stark, 1934; to Harold Clayton Urey, 1933, 1 letter [undated] on C. T. R. Wilson's recommendation for Nobel Prize; to A. B. Wood, 1917. Draft manuscript of obituary notice of Boltwood. Manuscript and typescript of obituary notice of Madame Curie. Obituary notice of Moseley. Rutherford's testimonial recommending Kapitsa for Trinity fellowship. Article, "Moseley's work on X-rays."
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 51 letters, 1923-1937. Letter to Georg von Hevesy, 1922.
    Bedford College Library, University of London, London, England. Letter to William Wilson, 1929.
    Royal Society Library, London, England. 70 letters, 1904-1930. 1 referee report, 1896.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. 4 letters to Julius Elster and Hans Geitel, 1899-1913; to Otto Hahn, 1908; to Heinrich Kayser, 1908; to Johannes Koenigsberger, 1909; to Marckwald, 1903. (Darmstaedter Collection, G1 1896).
    Deutsches Museum, Munich, Germany. Letter to Carl Runge, 1906.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Letter to Albert Einstein, 1930.
    American Institute of Physics, New York, New York. Letter to William Duane, 1908.
  - Catalog of Rutherford material in the Cavendish Laboratory, 1946; 8.0 p. (Reel 58, Reel-frame 4)
    Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1926-1937; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Rutten, L., (Louis), 1884-1946 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 18 August 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Saha, Meghnad, 1893-1956 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 8)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 6 letters, 1926-1946.
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Sambursky, Samuel, 1900-1990 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 1921-1924; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Sande Bakhuissen, W. H. van der (Reel 4, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Sanders, L. A. (Reel 14, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1950; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (12 pages); Sandham, H. F. (Reel 37, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Edwin A. Kemble, 26 March 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Saunders, Frederick A., (Frederick Albert), 1875-1963 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 8)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, 1925.
  - Letter to Werner Heisenberg, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Sauter, Fritz, 1906-1983 (Reel 45, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Sauter, Fritz, 1906-1983 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Sauvage Nolting, Willem Jacob Jan de (Reel 14, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 19 December 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schaefer, Clemens, 1878-1968 (Reel BSC 7, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 29 May 1921 - 6 July 1921; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Schaefer, Clemens, 1878-1968 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 1923; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Schaum, Karl, 1870-1947 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 25 July 1920 - 31 December 1922; 11.0 Item(s) 11 letters (12 pages); Scheel, Karl, 1866-1936 (Reel BSC 7, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 17 March 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Scheel, Karl, 1866-1936 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 6 July 1924 - 6 January 1925; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Scheel, Karl, 1866-1936 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 25 February 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Scheel, Karl, 1866-1936 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 7)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 6 letters, 1923-1928.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. 3 letters to Ludwig Darmstaedter, 1910-1919; 2 letters to Julius Hanauer, 1920-1927; 4 letters to Hans Schulz, 1925; letter to the Verein deutscher Ingenieure, 1894; 4 letters to Eilhard Wiedemann, 1908-1917. (Darmstaedter Collection, Fla* 1892).
    Bayerische Staatsbibliothek, Munich, Germany. Letter to P. von Groth, 1907. (Grothiana X).
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schenck, Rudolf, 1870-1965 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 22 October 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Scherrer, Paul, 1890-1969 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 24 July 1943; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Scherrer, Paul, 1890-1969 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 4 April 1919; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Scherrer, Paul, 1890-1969 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 19)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, 1941.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to M. Plancherel, 1933.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Schilthuis, Jan J. (Reel 14, Reel-frame 1, Reel 12)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1902; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (18 pages); Schlick, Otto, 1840-1913 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1911; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (6 pages); Schmidt, Heinrich Wilhelm, 1876-1914 (Reel 33, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936-1941; 7.0 Item(s) 7 letters (11 pages); Schmidt, Otto (Reel 33, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 1919; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schoenflies, A., (Arthur), 1853-1928 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 20)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1898-1899; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (9 pages); Schoenflies, A., (Arthur), 1853-1928 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schott, G. A., 1868-1937 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 9 November 1923; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Schottky, Walter, 1886-1976 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 11 May 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schottky, Walter, 1886-1976 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 1)
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 4 letters, 1914-1926.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941-1948; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (12 pages); Schouten, Jan Frederik, 1910-1980 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to H. Beutler, Circa 1926-1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, June 1921 - 28 June 1921; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel BSC 7, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Max Born, 2 November 1926 - 8 June 1927; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (11 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Charles Galton Darwin, 4 October 1927 - 22 October 1927; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 36, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to David Mathias Dennison, 18 June 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Eamon de Valéra, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letters to Benjamin Farrington, 1949; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (6 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Lloyd Frankenberg, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Irving John Good, 1960; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Walter Gordon, December 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Victor Hess, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to International Education Board, Circa 1926-1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to B. Jacoby, Circa 1926-1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Georg Joos, 17 November 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Pascual Jordan, 28 July 1927 - 18 November 1929; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 18, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 28 June 1921 - 19 November 1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (6 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 8, Reel 8, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 28 October 1925 - 28 June 1953; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (11 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 20, Reel 37, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Fritz London, 8 June 1926 - 7 December 1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (7 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to H. A. Lorentz, 23 June 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Charles Manneback, 25 January 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Henry Margenau, 1955; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to McCarthy, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Nature, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to John Von Neumann, 25 December 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 46, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Nobel Committee, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Notgemeinschaft der Deutschen Wissenschaft, Circa 1926-1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Wolfgang Pauli, 15 December 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Max Planck, 26 February 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letters to Michael Polanyi, 1949; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 3 October 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 17, Reel-frame B)
  - Letter to Charles Sherrington, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1937-1949; 14.0 Item(s) 14 letters (62 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 2, Reel 37, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Università di Bologna, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Gregor Wentzel, 11 May 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Hermann Weyl, 28 January 1943; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 14)
  - Letter to E. T. Whittaker, 29 March 1944; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 14)
    Includes statement on determinism and free will.
  - Letter to William Wilson, 16 April 1952; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Unidentified Correspondents, 1934-1943; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (19 pages); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 1)
  - Selected Correspondence and Papers, Bulk, 1933-1955; 1904-1960; 1.0 Reel(s); Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 92)
    Includes various correspondence, notes, lectures, articles, clippings. Detailed contents on reel.
    Materials selected by Linda Wessels from originals at Alpbach in the possession of Ruth Braunizer (daughter of Schrödinger).
  - Notebook from gymnasium, "Griechische Praeparationen," [Greek preparations], Before 1906; 29.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - Essay on Peano's postulates, "Über die Peanosche Punktmenge P.," removed from notebook entitled "Escherich, Funktionentheorie, 1907/08 Winter Sem. 2. Heft", 1907-1908; 20.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - Notes, "Vortrag Ramsay, Frühjahr 1908, Über seine neue Theorie der chemischen Verbindung und der Electricität," [Lecture by Sir William Ramsay, Spring 1908, about his new theory of the chemical compound and the electricity], 15.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - University notebook, "Przibram, Konstitution der Materie, Winter 1908," I. and II. Hefte, [Przibram, constitution of matter, Winter 1908, I and II Issues], 90.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - University notebook, "Phys. Seminar, Sommer 1909", Summer 1909; 15.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - University notebook, "Philosophie, 1910", 14.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - Two university notebooks, "Hasenöhrl Seminar 1910/11", 1910-1911; 37.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 1)
  - Book of physicists' addresses, Circa 1914; 34.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 2)
  - Diary and notebook, "Tagebuch 1915," [Diary 1915], 41.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 2)
  - Notebook, "Kausalität," [Causality], 10 September 1918; 3.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 7)
  - Three notebooks, "Tensoranalytische Mechanik", Circa 1918; 118.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 3)
  - Two unfinished manuscript drafts, "Hertz'sche Mechanik und Einstein'sche Gravitationstheorie," [Hertzian mechanics and Einstein's theory of gravitation], Circa 1918; 31.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 3)
  - Notebook, "Schwankungs Opaleszenz", Circa 1918; 19.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 4)
  - Notes, "Brown'sche Schwankungen des Drehwinkels," [Brownian fluctuations of the angle of rotation], Circa 1918; 15.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 4)
  - Two notebooks, "Besprechung der letzten Arbeiten Smoluchowskis," [Discussing the latest work of Smoluchowski], Circa 1918; 51.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 5)
  - Notes and three notebooks, "Privatum 1919", 103.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 6)
  - Notes on Kirchhoff's principle, Circa 1919; 20.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 6)
  - Eight notebooks, "Indische Philosophie und Religion," [Indian philosophy and religion], Circa 1905-1925; 156.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 7)
  - Notebook "Über Atomistik, mechanische Naturerklärung, und Phänomenologie," [About atomistic, mechanical explanation of nature, and phenomenology], Before 1920; 47.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 8)
  - Notebook, "Ad R. Avenarius", Before 1920; 16.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 39, Reel-frame 8)
  - Scrapbook of clippings of newspaper articles written by Schrödinger, 1923-1957; 75.0 p.; Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961 (Reel 43, Reel-frame 6)